<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Personal | DementRock's blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.rockyduan.com/blog/categories/personal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.rockyduan.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-05T16:55:39+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.rockyduan.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[DementRock]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2012 Begins]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.rockyduan.com/blog/2012/01/01/2012-begins/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-01T20:01:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.rockyduan.com/blog/2012/01/01/2012-begins</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I haven&#8217;t written such a thing as an annual summary for a very long time. It&#8217;s not that I&#8217;ve been busy, but I&#8217;m simply too lazy to write down these words. Instead I&#8217;ve too often kept these thoughts inside my head only.</p>

<p>Last year at the same time, I have just submitted my college applications. Then a few days later I began working on an MIT InvenTeam project in my high school. Interestingly, I have not joined the team until I happened to participate one of their team discussions and confidently promised that I had the skills to complete the project, which requires intensive web programming. But back to then, I knew nothing about web development at all. I was so lucky to have participated in this project because I received guidance from Tencent developers. I also learned a lot from a friend two grades lower than me. Without their help I might have spent much more time just to figure out what was actually going on.</p>

<p>Looking back, I have learned a lot about web during the year. Back to then, all I could include in my &#8220;resume&#8221; would be as following:</p>

<ul>
<li>Experience in C, C++, Pascal</li>

<li>Done over 400 problems on various online judges.</li>
</ul>

<p>Today the list of programming languages and techniques I&#8217;ve had experience is extended to Python, Ruby, Django, ROR, Java, Common Lisp, Javascript, Coffeescript, HTML, HAML, CSS, Sass, &#8230;</p>

<p>Comparing to what my peers have done, my experience is still far from enough. But I am still surprised by the progress I&#8217;ve made over the year.</p>

<p>What would I be if I did not happen to attend a team discussion and start the project? What would I be if I chose the common path as my other classmates and stay in China?</p>

<p>Life taught me not to ask these questions, since the progress of life itself is so delicate, so subtle, that I dare not to predict the outcome even with the slightest difference.</p>

<p>I cannot keep writing this way, or otherwise this post may never end. Let me just include some piece of thoughts this year:</p>

<ul>
<li>College does not matter that much. I was once frustrated for not getting into schools such as MIT, Stanford or CalTech. But what makes the difference is really YOURSELF.</li>

<li>Well, for the 4 months in Berkeley, I&#8217;ve experienced so many things: earthquate, fire in the same building I was living, streaking&#8230;</li>

<li>It feels really great when I ranked 1st in an Abstract Algebra midterm.</li>

<li>Playing piano is a great way to get rid of troubles.</li>

<li>The most valuable thing I&#8217;ve bought this year is not my Macbook Air, but the Virtual Private Server which costs me $3/month. I learned so much from it.</li>

<li>I cofounded an Acapella. It&#8217;s still being incubated, but I hope to give some performance in the new year.</li>

<li>I ended the relationship I&#8217;ve been in for two years. Well, some things only time may do.</li>

<li>I was once so determined to set Artificial Intelligence as my dream. But after the year, I am not sure any more because of my rising interest in so many fields. But still the greatest accomplishment I&#8217;ve tasted still comes from solving a hard algorithm or math problem. Taking a course in AI soon may be the best way to make the decision.</li>
</ul>

<p>Well, I&#8217;ve written a lot of nonsense. But the intention behind writing an annual summary is usually to set a goal for the new year. So here comes some plans:</p>

<ul>
<li>
<p>I REALLY need to do some sport. For the whole year I have spent most of my time indoors. For the new year, the plan is to run 20 miles per week.</p>
</li>

<li>
<p>Make more friends. Well I admit I&#8217;m antisocial&#8230;</p>
</li>

<li>
<p>Read 25 books.</p>
</li>

<li>
<p>I&#8217;m not sure yet how to set a goal for piano.</p>
</li>

<li>
<p>Start taking grad courses in math, statistics, and computer science.</p>
</li>
</ul>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
